他妈… 他妈的怎么回事
What the… What the fuck?
他妈…
What the…
他妈的怎么回事
What the fuck!
他妈的
Fuck.
有人吗？
Hello?
他妈的
Fuck.
你好 赛斯
Hello, Seth.
我要跟你玩个游戏
I wanna play a game.
现在 你一定感到很无助
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
- 这种无助… - 救命啊
- This is the same helplessness… - Help!
…你也曾给予他人
…you've bestowed onto others.
但现在轮到你来尝试一下了
But now it's onto you.
有人管这叫报应 我管这叫正义
Some call this karma. I call it justice.
到现在 你坐了五年牢
Now, you served five years…
但你所犯的谋杀罪本应判无期徒刑
…of what should have been a life sentence for murder.
法律空子让你重获了自由
A technicality gave you freedom…
但这阻止你…
…but it inhibited you…
…认识到夺人性命的严重后果
…from understanding the impact of taking a life.
今天 我要给你真正的自由
Today, I offer you true freedom.
30秒后
In 30 seconds,
钟摆会开始从你身边划过 然后逐渐逼近你
the pendulum will drop far enough to touch your body.
在60秒内 它将会把你切成两半
Within sixty seconds it will cut you in half.
要摆脱它
To avoid the pendulum,
你只要毁掉你用来杀人的工具
all you have to do is destroy the things that have killed…
你的双手
Your hands.
你要把你的手放进去
You must insert your hands…
按下按钮 开启你前面的装置
…and push the buttons to start the devices before you.
然后你的骨头会被粉碎
Your bones will be crushed to dust.
你会牺牲「杀人工具」…
Will you destroy the things…
…来拯救另一生命吗？赛斯
…that have taken life in order to save one, Seth?
做抉择吧！
Make your choice.
不要
No.
那是意外
It was an accident!
求你了
Please.
好吧！去你妈的
Okay. Fuck you.
好的 好的
Okay. Okay. Okay.
我照你说的做了
I did what I was supposed to do.
《电锯惊魂5》
让我看你的手 让我看你他妈的手
Let me see your hands. Let me see your fucking hands.
我女儿在哪 你…
Where is my daughter? You…
天啊
Jesus.
你好 斯莱姆探员
Hello, Agent Strahm.
如果你听到这个录音
If you're hearing this,
那说明你已经找到了你要找的东西
then you've finally found what you've been looking for.
但找到我的尸体对你来说足够了吗？
But is the discovery of my body enough?
还是说 你对揭开真相的巨大渴望…
Or will your insatiable hunger…
…会让你走进更深的无底洞
…to uncover the truth push you deeper into the abyss?
听从我的忠告 不要再深入了
Heed my warning. Do not proceed.
因为这房间 既可以是你的圣所
For this room can either be your sanctuary…
也可以是你的坟墓
…or it can be your grave.
你来决定吧！
The choice is yours.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
嘿
Hey!
救命啊…
Help!
进去 进去
Go! Go!
你没事了
You're okay.
- 我爸爸在哪 - 他会没事的
- Where's my dad? - He's gonna be okay.
我妈妈呢 我妈妈呢
Where's my mom? Where's my mom?
- 霍夫曼 - 我来 我来
- Hoffman. - I got it. I got it.
你可以走路吗？
You okay to walk?
到底怎么了 伙计 发生了什么事 里格在哪
What the hell, man? What happened? Where's Rigg?
尽力了 他没活过来
Tried to help. He didn't make it.
所有人都没有
Nobody made it.
我们找到个生还者
We got a live one.
有人吗？
Hello?
马上
Right away.
塔克女士
Ms. Tuck.
坐下吧！
Have a seat.
很高兴见到你 菲尔德曼先生
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Feldman.
我为什么要来这里
Why am I here?
我代表你的前任丈夫约翰
I represent your ex- husband, John.
按照指示 在他去世后 我要联系你
In the event of his death, I was instructed to contact you.
我想你也明白我有多惊讶
You can understand my surprise…
在我知道他的身份后
…when I found out who he really was.
约翰留了些东西给你
John left something for you.
如果你在看着这录影
If you're watching this,
吉尔 我已经不在人世了
Jill, I'm long gone from this world.
你是我的最爱 一直都是 永远都是
You are my heart, you always have been. You always will be.
我不会去解释我最近的行为
I'm not going to try to explain my actions of late.
或者说 我很难原谅自己
Suffice it to say that I find it difficult to forgive myself…
对在诊所所发生的事情
…for what happened at the clinic.
我允许了 确切地说
I permitted, indeed,
我鼓励了你去帮助那里的人
encouraged your decisions regarding the people there.
我预见到危险 我应该有所行动的
I saw danger and l… I should have acted sooner.
现在我给你留了个盒子
I'm leaving you a box today,
现在里面的东西很重要
and its contents are of grave importance.
就算我们不是对所有事都持相同意见
Even though you and I don't always see eye to eye on everything…
但我相信你会知道
…I deeply believe in you and I believe that you will know…
怎样处理里面的东西
…what to do with these materials.
我要感谢你们今天来到这里
I wanna thank you all for coming here today.
我想作为第一个人告诉你们
And I'd like to be the first to say…
竖锯杀人案已经结束
…that the Jigsaw murders are over.
那些牺牲了姓名的探员今天将得到缅怀
The officers who gave their lives are being honored here today.
但今天我要把一份特别的荣誉
But today I'd like to offer a special honor…
交给一名从一开始…
…to the detective who's been…
…就着手这个案件的探员
…on this case right from the beginning…
他通过无私的奉献
…who proved through hard work and dedication…
确保了其他探员没有白白牺牲
…that the people who died did not die in vain.
今天我们把荣耀交给刚提拔的中尉
Today we honor the newly promoted Detective Lieutenant…
马克·霍夫曼
…Mark Hoffman.
恭喜
Congratulations.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
谢谢你们 非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
嗯…
Uh, ahem…
通过这次考验 如果说我们学到了什么的话 就是
Throughout this ordeal, if we've learned anything it's that…
生命是神圣的
…human life is sacred.
我们学到 每一天
And we've learned that every day…
我们都要珍惜生命
…life should be cherished.
正义
Justice…
是带来和平社会的基石
…is the backbone to every peaceful society.
我相信 正义已得到伸张
And I believe that true justice has been served.
霍夫曼探员 医院有人找你
Detective Hoffman, you're wanted at the hospital.
是关于彼瑞兹探员的
It's about Agent Perez.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 彼瑞兹探员
Hello, Agent Perez,
欢迎来到你专研已久的世界
and welcome to the world that you have long studied.
听从我的忠告 彼瑞兹探员
Heed my warning, Agent Perez.
你的下一步行动很重要
Your next move is critical.
- 开门 - 那是什么
- Open the door. - What is that?
我扶你 我扶你
I got you.
我对彼瑞兹探员发生的事深表遗憾
I'm truly sorry about Agent Perez.
她说了你的名字 你知道吗？
She said your name, you know.
她的遗言是「霍夫曼探员」
The last thing she said was "Detective Hoffman."
她为什么会那么说 她为什么会提到你的名字
Why'd she say that? Why'd she say your name?
- 我不知道 - 不知道吗？
- I don't know. - No?
你是怎么逃出那建筑物的
How'd you walk out of that building?
你是怎么做到的
How did you?
他妈的我在我自己的喉咙上开了个洞
On a gurney with a fucking hole in my throat.
而你呢
Look at you.
只有几处瘀伤 和一个你挣脱了绳索的故事
Couple of scratches and a story about how your arm straps broke.
竖锯是不会犯错的
Jigsaw doesn't make mistakes.
这是你的又一个推论吗？因为竖锯死了
Is this you theorizing again? Because Jigsaw's dead.
我不是在说他
I'm not talking about him,
我是在说你的整个欺诈部门
I'm talking about you and your whole crooked department.
我的部门已经没有了 他们都死了 一个人也不剩
My department's gone. They're all dead. There's no one left.
除了你
Besides you.
我从一开始就在追捕竖锯
Been chasing Jigsaw from the beginning…
而最后我做到了
…and I got him.
所以除非你还有什么重要的话要说
So unless you've got something else to say…
他妈的别来烦我
…back the fuck off.
看看报纸吧！我救了那小女孩
Read the papers. I saved that little girl.
彼瑞兹探员的事情很遗憾
Sorry about Agent Perez.
你不是应该休息一下吗？
Shouldn't you be resting?
我没事 埃里克森
I'm fine, Erickson.
不是的 彼得 所以我才让你休病假了
No, you're not, Peter. That's why I put you on medical leave.
我本来应该死于那陷阱的
I was supposed to die in that trap.
你不应该独自一人去那里
You never should have been there without backup.
我要和吉尔·塔克再谈一次
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time.
你已经不再负责这个案件了
You're no longer handling the case, Peter.
什么
What?
读一下吧！
Read it.
在现场发现了超过十二具尸体
Over a dozen dead bodies were recovered at the scene,
包括两名警察
two of which were cops.
竖锯死了 我一共救了多少生命啊
Jigsaw's dead, how many lives did I inevitably save?
通过置自己与他人于危险中
By endangering yourself and others.
你不再负责这个案件了
You're off the case.
谁的命令
On whose orders?
我的
Mine.
很抱歉 彼得 已经结束了
I'm sorry, Peter. It's over.
噢 天啊
Oh, my God.
噢
Oh…
- 这是什么 - 嘿 不要动
- What is this? - Hey, don't move.
你对我做了什么
What did you do to me?
我什么也没做
I didn't do anything.
- 是竖锯 - 什么
- It's Jigsaw. - What?
我就知道这会发生在我身上的 这就是他的作风
I knew this was gonna happen to me. This is what he does.
不 不是竖锯
No, it's not Jigsaw.
他已经死了
He's dead.
你最近没看新闻吗？
Haven't you watched TV lately?
是啊 好吧！不管是谁做的
Yeah, well, whoever it is…
我们正被观察着
…they're watching us.
以确保我们遵守规则
To make sure we follow the rules.
- 什么跟什么啊 - 如果我是你的话 我就不会那样做了
- Which are what? - I wouldn't do that if I were you.
除非你想让自己的头像蒲公英一样开花
Unless you want your head to pop off like a dandelion.
- 你怎么知道的 - 因为我是长眼睛的
- How do you know that? - Because I have eyes.
只要有人拉动钢索 我们身上的计时器就会启动
One pull- pin starts the timer for all of us.
除非你知道它是怎么运作的 你是不会拉动的
You won't wanna do that unless you know how it works,
对吧！
now, would you?
你开始吓到我了 伙计
You're starting to freak me out, dude.
大家好 欢迎来到这里
Hello, and welcome.
自出娘胎以来 你们就比其他人有更多的优势
From birth, you've all been given the advantages of few others.
然而通过一些不道德的抉择
Yet through poor moral decisions…
你们利用这些优势 自私地
…you've used these advantages to selfishly further…
让自己更受益 而牺牲他人的利益
…only yourselves at the expense of others.
今天这种想法将会得到考验
Well, today this singular way of thinking will be put to the test.
现在 五人连成一线 都有着相同的目标 存活
Today, five will become one, with a common goal of survival.
你们互相联系着
You are all connected.
一条钢索穿过了你们脖子上的装置
A cable runs through your collar devices.
如果绳索被拉紧的话
It can be pulled so tight…
你们将会被身后设置好的剃刀斩首
…that you will be decapitated on the mounted razors.
唯一将项圈拿掉的方法就是
The only way to remove the collar is…
…使用玻璃盒子里的钥匙
…with the keys from the glass boxes…
他们放在你们面前的台座上
…on the pedestals before you.
然而 你们有一个人移动去取钥匙的话
However, if one of you moves to retrieve a key…
你们所有人的60秒计时器都会启动
…the 60- second timer will begin for you all.
面对这种情况
In choosing how to react to this situation…
你们的本能会驱使你们做出行动
…your lifelong instincts will tell you to do one thing…
但我恳求你们做出相反的行动
…but I implore you to do the opposite.
让游戏开始吧！
Let the games begin.
总会有人死掉的
Somebody has to die.
不不不 他说 「不要相信你的本能」
No, no, no, it says, "Don't listen to your instincts."
- 意思就是 不要去拿钥匙 - 你他妈的是傻B吗？
- That means don't go for the keys. - You fucking nuts?
如果我们不去取钥匙 我们要怎么存活
How are we supposed to live if we don't?
- 他在测试我们的忍耐力 - 我们得行动了 宝贝
- It's testing our endurance. - We gotta move, babe.
计时器是连着那些罐子的
That timer's connected to those jars.
他没提到那些罐子
It didn't say anything about those jars.
- 可能没联系的 - 他们是炸弹
- They could be nothing. - They're nail bombs.
自制的 很可能是C- 4
Homemade, probably C- 4.
你他妈的怎么知道这些的
How the fuck do you know that?
她是防火检查员 她见过这些鬼东西
She's a fire inspector. She's seen all kinds of demented shit.
你怎么认识我的
How do you know me?
嘿 伙计 她在问你问题 你怎么认识她的
Hey, man, she's asking you a question. How do you know her?
你怎么认识她的 回答我
How do you know her? Answer me!
听着 我们都冷静下来
Look, let's just keep our cool.
- 好吧！我们会想到办法的 - 我们在这里是有原因的
- Okay, we can figure this out. - We're all here for a reason.
好吧！根据信息 我们都是有联系的
Okay, and we're all connected, as the message said.
我们只要…
We just need to…
- 你是从事什么的 - 你先说
- What did you do? - You go first.
他说我们一出生就占有优势
It said that we were all born with advantages.
对吧！？也就是说我们都来自富有人家
Right? That means we're all from money.
- 我不是 - 我也不是
- I'm not. - And neither am I.
嘿 他妈的说得好 南茜·朱尔（小说中的少女侦探）
Hey, nice fucking try, Nancy Drew.
那到底是什么意思
Well, then, what does it mean?
我们利用与生俱来的优势做了些坏事
We did something wrong with an advantage from birth.
那不一定就是指钱
That doesn't have to mean money.
你有什么没告诉我们的
What are you not telling us? Huh?
你知道她的事情 你还知道我们什么事
You know about her, what do you know about the rest of us?
他妈的你能跟我说话吗？
Would you fucking talk to me?
- 冷静 - 我他妈的很冷静
- Relax. - I am fucking relaxed.
这是游戏 兄弟
It's a game, tweaker.
明白吗？你知道我的事越少就越好
Get it? The less you know about me, the better.
你他妈的在这里逞英雄的理由
The reason why you fucked up your charmed existence…
我们都很清楚 不是吗？
…is pretty obvious to everyone, isn't it?
去你妈的 去你妈的
Fuck you. Fuck you.
我们都玩过火 不是吗？
Been playing with matches again, have we?
你们都他妈的去死 去你妈的计划
Fuck all of you and your fucking plan.
除非你们想被炸得粉身碎骨
Unless you wanna be shredded when those bombs go off…
我建议我们还是行动吧！
…I suggest we move on.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
做个聪明人
Being smart.
这里是特勤探员斯莱姆的办公室
Special Agent Strahm's office.
我是霍夫曼探员 斯莱姆探员现在方便吗？
This is Detective Hoffman. Is Agent Strahm available?
他不方便 但我可以给你联系特勤探员埃里克森
He's not, but I can connect you to Special Agent Erickson.
他处理所有的询问
He's handling all inquiries.
拜托你了
Please.
你接通了埃里克森探员的留言信箱
You've reached the voice mail box of Agent Erickson.
请留言
Please leave a message.
我是霍夫曼探员
Yeah, this is Detective Hoffman.
我要和斯莱姆探员讨论一些事情
I needed to discuss something with Agent Strahm…
但我找不到他
…but I can't seem to track him down.
你能给我回个电话吗？我会很感激的
Could you give me a call? It would be greatly appreciated.
找到你了
There you are.
是你妹妹啊
Sister.
彼得
Peter.
- 科万 把这拿去分析 - 马上去 先生
- Cowan, take this to analysis. - Right away, sir.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
只是回办公室拿点东西 我接受你的建议
Just grabbing some stuff from the office. I'm taking your advice.
让自己休假？
Taking some time off, huh?
是的 我需要时间康复
Yeah, well, I have to heal up, you know.
好的
Mm- hm.
好吧！保持联系 先再见了
You know, I'll keep in touch. I'll see you around.
霍夫曼
Hoffman.
我们发现了另一具尸体 看起来像是竖锯的实验品
We got another body. Looks like another Jigsaw victim.
- 你要查一下吗？- 好的
- You up for this? - Yeah.
典型的谋杀犯
Typical bio. Murder convict.
坐了5年牢 上个月才被释放
Served five years, just released last month.
我认识他
I know him.
他叫赛斯·巴克斯特
His name's Seth Baxter.
我妹妹的前男友
My sister's ex- boyfriend.
他就是杀了你妹妹的人？
This is the guy that murdered your sister?
他被判了25年
He was sentenced to 25 years.
钻法律空子 减到了5年
Got it reduced to five on a technicality.
那我只能说 正义得到伸张了
Well, then I'd say justice was served.
你杀了他 让这看起来像是竖锯布下的陷阱
You killed him. Made it look like a Jigsaw trap.
我逮到你了
I got you.
- 还不行 - 别关门 会启动计时器的
- Not yet. - Don't close the door. It'll set off the timer.
- 你确定吗？- 常理来说
- Do you know that for sure? - Educated guess.
我们需要做的是 了解各自的身份
What we need to do is figure out who everyone is.
好的 我们知道…
Okay, well, we know…
…刚才死去的女人是消防部的
…that the dead woman worked for the fire department.
不再是了 她一个月前被解雇了
Not anymore. She got canned a month ago.
你他妈的… 你他妈的怎么会知道
How the fuck do you… How the fuck do you know that?
你要对这负责任 他妈的她的头被砍掉了
You're responsible for this? She had her fucking head cut off!
我要关门
I'm closing the door.
- 我要关上这他妈的门 - 安静点
- I'm gonna close the fucking door! - Just be quiet.
拜托
Please.
你的故事又是什么
What's your story?
我是城市规划局的
I work for the Department of City Planning.
- 结婚了吗？有孩子吗？- 没有结婚 没有孩子
- Married? Kids? - No, and no.
- 轮到你了 - 你不打算告诉他们你父亲的事？
- Your turn. - You're not gonna tell them about Daddy?
- 我父亲是理查德·吉布斯 - 美洲狮集团的老总？
- My dad is Richard Gibbs. - The owner of the Cougars?
多年来 他一直想建个体育场
He's been trying to build a new stadium for years.
他不知道的是
Little did he know…
他只需要等他女儿…
…all he had to do is wait for his daughter…
…在城市规划局找到工作
…to get a job in City Planning.
你呢 你的故事是什么
And you. What about you?
你又干了些什么狗屎肮脏事
What sort of shady shit have you been up to?
我是一个房地产发展公司的副总裁
I'm a senior V.P. For a real estate development company.
那么说你也很无聊了
So you're boring too. Hmm?
马诗福德集团 在这个城市 不通过城市规划局
The Marshvard Group. Yeah, you can't get a permit in this town…
你是拿不到许可的
…without going through the Department of City Planning.
- 对吗？- 对 没错
- Right? - No, you can't.
你呢
What about you?
呃…
Uh…
没有老婆
No wife.
没有我知道的孩子 没有工作
No kids that I know of. No job.
信托基金养大的 有人觉得惊讶吗？
Trust-fund baby. Anyone surprised?
我他妈的受够你的自以为是了
I'm so fucking sick of your self- righteousness.
轮到你了
It's your turn.
我是先锋报上的调查记者
I'm an investigative journalist for The Herald.
先锋报？那就是你的成就？
Herald? That's your accomplishment?
你给一家八卦小报社工作？
You work for a gossip rag?
他妈的咬你自己的舌头吧！
Bite your fucking tongue.
那些罐里的是什么鬼东西啊
What the hell are in those jars?
在炸弹爆炸前 我们快点解决这事吧！
Let's do this fucking thing before the bombs go off.
他妈的
Fuck!
大家好 欢迎来到下一堂课
Hello, and welcome to the next lesson.
墙里面有四个洞
These walls hold four chambers.
这些洞是安全的
These chambers are for safety.
然而 必须有钥匙才能进入
However, to access them, a key is needed.
但只有三枚钥匙是能开锁的
But only three of the keys will fit the locks.
这些钥匙就在挂在屋顶的罐里
These keys are in the glass jars hanging from the ceiling.
要快点行动了 因为当时间倒数完的时候
Move quickly, though, because when the clock ticks down…
房间角落的炸弹就会被引爆
…the explosives in the corners of the room will detonate.
现在只有三个安全洞
With only three points of safety,
你们到底谁会出局呢
which of you will be the odd man out?
做抉择吧！
Make your choice.
他妈的
Fuck.
他妈的 是平的 要找个有形状的
Fuck, it's blank. I need a shape.
别碰那里 你哪里也去不了
Get your hands off that, you're not going anywhere.
- 不要这样 - 清醒吧！你他妈的婊子
- Stop it! - Get a clue, you fucking bitch.
现在是适者生存
It's survival of the fittest.
平的
Blank.
该死
Shit.
找到了 我找到了
I got it. Got it.
太好了
Yes.
祝你下次走运 老兄
Better luck next time, rich boy.
适者生存 吃屎去
Survival of the fittest, my ass!
等一下
Wait.
关于赛斯·巴克斯特的案件
Everything all right with Detective Kerr…
克瑞探员都没问题吧！
…in the Seth Baxter case?
- 是的 - 很好
- Yeah. - Good.
菲斯克 随时向我汇报
Fisk. You keep me posted.
- 知道了 - 好的
- Will do. - Good.
赛斯的案件后 你就参与每次有关竖锯的调查
After Seth, you were involved in every investigation.
你第一次见竖锯是什么时候
When did you first meet Jigsaw?
住手 住手
Stop it, stop it!
不要
Don't!
快走 我说
Heel! Heel, I said!
别刺激他 混蛋
Don't provoke him. Asshole!
我的天啊 拜托 皮威 快点
Jesus Christ. Come on, Peewee. Come on.
- 快点 皮威 - 皮威
- Come on, Peewee. - Peewee.
该死的
Shit.
你介意吗？
Do you mind?
- 上去？- 是的 谢谢
- Going up? - Yes, thank you.
你要去哪层
What floor are you going to?
我想我们的目的地是一样的
I think we're both going to the same place.
你知道你为什么会在这里 对吧！
You know why you're here, don't you?
他们说 模仿是最诚挚的奉承
They say imitation is the sincerest form of flattery.
但不知怎的 我觉得因别人的艺术
But I find it somewhat distasteful…
而自己得到功劳 心里很不爽
…to be given credit for work that's not mine.
尤其是那些稍逊一筹的艺术
Especially inferior work.
和你一样 我知道失去家人是什么滋味
Like you, I know what it's like to lose family.
我知道保护不了心爱的人的滋味
I know what it's like not to be able to protect loved ones.
是种很无助的感受
It's a powerless feeling.
我不会那么做
I wouldn't do that.
微力扳机
Hair trigger.
你看到了什么
What do you see?
嗯？
Hm?
复仇可以改变一个人 让你成为
Vengeance can change a person. Make you into something…
你永远也想不到的人
…you never thought you were capable of being.
但不像你 我从没杀过任何人
But unlike you, I've never killed anyone.
- 我会给他们机会 - 你把这叫机会吗？
- I give people a chance. - You call this a chance?
我们看着吧！
We'll see.
我们的游戏才刚开始
Our game's just begun.
我们的游戏？你根本不认识我
Our game? You don't even know me.
我认识你 在你追捕我的时候 我也在跟踪你
I know you. I followed you as you've pursued me.
我认识你 我也知道你妹妹的事
I know you. I know about your sister.
我知道你有多关心她
I know how you cared for her.
我知道她是你唯一的家人
I know she was your only family.
放开我
Leave me alone.
不
No!
你坐在酒吧！里直到它打烊
You sit in bars until closing.
你喝酒 这样你才能入睡
You drink so you can sleep.
你醉乎乎地走向你的车
You stagger to your car…
下一天又重复同样的事情
…and then you start it all over again the next day.
接着我发现了你做什么来消遣
Then I discovered what you do for recreation.
嗯
Mm.
你可以抛弃正义
You can dispense justice…
同一时候 又给予他们一个机会…
…and give people a chance to value their lives…
…来衡量他们的性命
…in the same moment.
顺带一提
And by the way…
你那钟摆上的刀锋是劣质品
…the blade on your pendulum was inferior.
如果你要它真正锋利的话
If you want a true edge…
你得要用经过锻造的钢
…you have to used tempered steel.
那样才能持久
Tempering's better for the long haul.
你也为了个持久的目标吧！探员？
You in this for the long haul, detective?
我已经当了20年警察 对你来说足够长了吗？
I been a cop for 20 years. Is that long enough for you?
那你和我都应该知道…
Then you and I both know…
…这城市里重复犯罪的人的数目
…the statistics for repeat offenders in this city.
67.5%的罪犯在三年内会再次进入监狱
67.5 percent of criminals are back in prison within three years.
你想我怎么做
What do you want from me?
你也许觉得
So you might look at…
你对赛斯所做的事是为民除害
…what you did to Seth as a kind of public service.
她是我唯一的家人 他不该得到任何机会
She was my only family. He didn't deserve a chance.
- 他是禽兽 - 每个人都应该得到一次机会
- He was an animal. - Everybody deserves a chance!
你没看到那血泊
You didn't see the blood!
你没看到他妈的他对她做了什么
You didn't see what he fucking did to her!
杀人对我来说是
Killing is distasteful…
不合口味的
…to me.
有一种更好 更有效率的方式
There is a better, more efficient way.
你看到了什么 看
What do you see? Look!
- 你看到了什么 - 告诉我你想要什么
- What do you see? - Tell me what you want.
我要知道 你是否有生存下去的勇气
I wanna know if you have what it takes to survive.
去你妈的
Fuck you.
你明白吗？这就是我所说的不同方法
You see, it's a different method that I'm talking about.
如果测试对象从我的游戏中生存下来
If a subject survives my method…
他们将会得到重生
…he or she is instantly rehabilitated.
好吧！你要一次机会吗？
Now, you want a chance?
你要一次机会吗？
You want a chance?
我会给你一次机会
I'll give you a chance.
我是你称之为竖锯的人
I'm the man you call Jigsaw.
逮捕我是你的责任
It's your duty to bring me in…
但我知道你是谁
…but I know who you are…
我知道你做了什么
…and I know what you鈥檝e done.
那么说这是勒索
So this is blackmail.
不不不
No, no, no.
这是赎罪
This is redemption.
只是给你一个选择 仅此而已
Just giving you an option, that's all.
现在 你可以逮捕我
Now, you can arrest me…
但这么做的话 你的人生就结束了 你是知道的
…but doing so, your life ends as you know it.
或者
Or…
你可以去探索
…you could explore…
一种让罪犯重生的方法
…a method of rehabilitation…
使你夜晚能安睡
…that'll permit you to sleep at night.
或者我可以现在就杀了你
Or I could kill you right now.
但你不是一个真正的杀手
But you're not a true killer.
那是你的困境
That's your dilemma…
而且我对你所了解的信息
…and the information that I have on you…
正位于一个很适合的地方
…is exactly where it needs to be…
随着我的消失 那信息将会被公布
…and it will be released in the event of my disappearance.
与其信你 他们会更信任我的话
They'll never believe your word over mine.
你愿意冒这个险吗？
You willing to take that risk?
毁灭你一生
Risk of ruining your own life…
为了保护一个释放杀人犯的
…in order to protect a corrupt legal system…
腐败的法律系统
…that puts murderers back on the streets?
你妹妹会怎么想
How would your sister feel?
你正站在交叉路上 探员
You're at a crossroads, detective.
做抉择吧！
Make your choice.
你帮助竖锯把那些受害者抓了？
Did you help Jigsaw get all of them?
霍夫曼探员 这位是特勤探员埃里克森
Detective Hoffman, this is Special Agent Erickson.
关于竖锯的案件 你有什么要讨论的吗？
You had something you needed to discuss about the Jigsaw case?
是的 我今晚去了斯莱姆探员的病房
Yes. I stopped by Agent Strahm's room tonight at the hospital,
但他不在那
but he wasn't there.
- 希望他没事吧！- 噢 是的 他很好
- I hope he's all right. - Oh, yeah, he's fine.
斯莱姆在推断除了阿曼达·杨
Agent Strahm was theorizing about the possibility…
竖锯还有另一个同谋的可能性
…of an additional accomplice to Jigsaw, other than Amanda Young.
某个我们目前还不知道的人
Someone who might be currently unknown.
他有向你提过类似的事情吗？
Did he ever mention anything like that to you?
没有 而且 我是刚加入这个案件的
No, but then again, I'm new to the case.
是的 也许你可以…
Yeah, well, maybe you could…
…让他尽快联系我
…get him to contact me at his earliest convenience.
知道了 还有…
Will do. And…
依你看
…in your theorizing…
你觉得谁会是同谋
…who exactly did you suspect would be an accomplice?
他怀疑是内部的人
Well, he suspected someone on the inside.
一个有权限的人
Someone with access.
很有趣的推理
It's an interesting theory.
探员 我们明早见个面吧！
Detective, what do you say we reconnect in the morning?
好的
You got it.
死路
Dead.
那人是混蛋 但他很聪明
That guy was an asshole, but he was smart.
他对我们还有用处
We could've used him.
是啊 但总要有人死的
Yeah, well, someone had to die.
你要做那个牺牲者吗？
Would you rather it'd been you?
他们是怎么抓住你的
How'd they get you?
去你的
Screw you!
我要杀了你 我要杀了你
I'm gonna kill you! I'm gonna kill you!
我要杀…
I'm gonna kill…
你好 保罗
Hello, Paul.
你自残 是因为你真的在寻死
Did you cut yourself because you truly wanted to die…
还是因为你想得到关注
…or did you just want some attention?
今晚 你将会告诉我
Tonight, you'll show me.
如果你要活下去的话 你得再次自残
If you want to live, you'll have to cut yourself again.
你愿意流掉多少血来保命呢 保罗
How much blood will you shed to stay alive, Paul?
我没想过会感到自责
I didn't expect to feel any remorse.
要冷静下来
The heart cannot be involved.
感情用事的话 就什么也办不到了
Emotionally, there can be nothing there.
永远不要投入私人感情
It can never be personal.
- 我们走吧！- 不能
- Let's go. - No.
你的事情还没完
You're not done yet.
今晚你会看到…
Tonight you will see…
…杀戮与救赎的区别
…the difference between killing and rehabilitation.
还有一个你需要注意的探员
There is another detective that you should be aware of.
他叫泰普
His name's Tapp.
他很聪明 而且快接近真相了
He's smart, and he's getting closer.
我知道他是谁
I know who he is.
我要你帮我把他引向某个人
I need you to lead him to someone for me.
一个医生
A doctor.
一个需要被医治的医人者
A healer who needs some healing.
这是你的吗？医生
Is this yours, doctor?
你提供了这些警局里的档案 对吧！
You supplied these police files, didn't you?
你觉得事情会照你所想发展
You're assuming this is gonna play out the way you want it.
我没设想任何事
I assume nothing.
我只是猜测可能性 我让游戏自行开始
I anticipate the possibilities, and I let the game play out.
那你为什么需要阿曼达参与这游戏
Then why do you need Amanda in the game?
确保游戏规则被遵守
To ensure that the rules are followed.
她不会替任何人做决定 她只会…
She won't make decisions for anyone. She'll just…
提供选择
…offer choices.
靠左边一点
Little to your left.
那很多事情都要看偶然了
That leaves a lot to chance.
如果你擅长猜测人的思维
If you're good at anticipating the human mind…
偶然就会变成必然了
…it leaves nothing to chance.
是时候了
It's time.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
太好了 又有炸弹
Great. More bombs.
好吧！你做了什么事 才会被抓到这里来
All right. What'd you do to get here?
我…我做了些事 一群人遇害了
L… I did something, and a bunch of people were killed.
我是无意的
I didn't mean to.
但他们确实是死了
They're still dead.
- 这就是你在这里的原因？- 是的
- That's why you're here? - Yeah.
做了这种事 你不应该要坐牢吗？
Shouldn't you have gone to jail for something like that?
没人知道
Nobody else knows.
看来某人知道了
Somebody does.
我没杀任何人 如果这是你的问题的话
I didn't kill anybody, if that's what you're asking.
我没有想过这么问
I wasn't.
我通过了某个建楼的提议
I grant building permits.
没错 也许有些人比其他人更值得拥有
And yeah, some people might have been more deserving than others…
但你知道吗？这是做生意
…but you know what? That's the business.
所以如果有人跟你说不同的想法 他们只是愚蠢
So if someone tells you different, then they're just stupid.
或者天真 或者两者都是
Or naive. Or both.
屁话
Bullshit.
你接受贿赂 你是他妈的骗子
You take bribes. You're a fucking liar.
你欺骗大众 那样很不好
You cheat people. That's not nice.
是的
Yeah, well.
我想她也算不上圣母吧！
I'm sure she's not exactly Mother Teresa either.
不 我不是
No, I'm not.
我在人口最密集的城市…
I build condos in one of the most densely…
…建了个公寓
…populated cities in the country.
但你总不能不拆掉旧楼就建新楼吧！
You don't put up a new building without tearing down a few old ones.
所以我们这类狗屎来到这里都是应得的
So we're all bags of shit that deserve to be here.
很好 太好了
That's good. That's great.
他妈的太好了
Fucking great.
你觉得就是这原因？
So is that what you think this is?
你不觉得还有其他联系吗？
You don't think there's any other connection?
不 我觉得有
No, I do.
我是这么觉得 但我不管
I do. And I don't give a shit.
关上那他妈的门 我们来听规则吧！
Close the fucking door. We have to hear the rules.
你们好 欢迎来到这里
Hello, and welcome.
你们一定很渴望…
You must all be eager…
…上下一堂改变自身的课了吧！
…to learn the next important lesson in your transformation.
下一个游戏是为了架起桥梁
The game before you is designed…
修补你们之间的分歧
…to bridge the gap between you all.
要打开这房间门上的五把锁
In order to open the five locks on the door out of this room…
必须得关掉连通着的五个电路
…the five electrical circuits powering them must be closed.
唯一的办法就是
The only way to do this is…
让五根电线都接上浴缸里的水
…to find a way to connect all five cords to the bath water.
电路被关上后 门就会打开了
Close the circuits and the door will open.
但你们要快点行动了
But you must work quickly…
因为三分钟后
…for in three minutes,
一股电流将会通过这房间
an electrical current will surge through this room…
那时候门会被永远锁上
…locking the door forever.
谁要做那桥梁呢 做抉择吧！
Who will bridge the gap? The choice is yours.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ.
这不够长 他妈的我们要怎么做啊
It's not gonna reach. How the fuck are we gonna do this?
想想办法吧！
Come on!
你要进浴缸去
You're gonna get in the tub…
我们要把五根电线接在你身上
…and we're gonna connect the five cords to you.
但你同时也会要了我的命
But you're gonna kill me too.
- 进去 - 是啊 我看起来更像是会洗澡的人
- Get in. - Yeah, I'm more of a shower guy.
可我现在不想这么做
I don't think I'm gonna do that right now.
他妈的进浴缸去
Get in the fucking tub.
去你妈的 你这贱货 他妈的你进去
Fuck you, you bitch. You get in the fucking tub.
不 不要这么做
No, don't do it.
求你了 不要
Please, no.
你杀了她 你他妈的杀了她
You killed her. You fucking killed her.
我不信任她
I didn't trust her.
我的天啊 你们俩有什么恩怨
Jesus Christ. What is it with you two?
闭上嘴 帮我移动尸体吧！
Just shut up and help me with the body.
嘿 嘿 不要 不要让你的身体接触她
Hey, hey. No. Don't let your body touch hers.
噢 天啊 是个钩子
Oh, my God, it's a hook.
把这插进她头里 要不我们就出不去了
Stick it in her head or we don't get out.
动手吧！
Just do it.
进来
Come in.
先生 是吉尔·塔克
Sir. It's Jill Tuck.
晚上好
Good evening.
我是特勤探员埃里克森
Special Agent Erickson.
谢谢你这么晚还来见我
Thank you for seeing me so late in the day.
不客气
Not a problem.
没你的事了
That'll be all.
请坐
Please, have a seat.
那么我们有什么能帮到你的
So, what do you need from us?
我觉得我被跟踪了
I think I'm being followed.
那更应该去找警察啊 塔克小姐
Well, that sounds more like police work, Miss Tuck.
我觉得他们帮不到我
I don't think they can help me.
- 因为？- 因为是你们FBI的人
- Because? - Because it's you. The FBI.
我不明白
I don't understand.
从约翰开始被确认为竖锯杀人犯时就开始了
It started when John was first identified as the Jigsaw killer.
那时候我不感到惊讶 但现在我还是感觉被跟踪
It didn't surprise me then, but I'm still being followed.
被谁 塔克小姐 谁会跟踪你
By who, Miss Tuck? Who would be following you?
我想是那个审问我的探员
I think it's the agent who interrogated me.
斯莱姆探员
Agent Strahm.
- 他为什么要跟踪你呢 - 我不知道
- And why would he be following you? - I don't know.
- 你还把这事跟其他人说了吗？- 只跟你说了
- Who else have you told about this? - Only you.
阿曼达是怎么回事
What's going on with Amanda?
你不是告诉我 要启蒙他人
Didn't you tell me the only way to truly offer enlightenment…
切忌感情用事吗？
…is by detaching emotionally?
但你可以拥有阿曼达所没有的东西
But you can have something Amanda doesn't.
匿名
Anonymity.
那是最好的保护 那是我所赋予你的
That's the greatest protection. That's what I've given you.
我要你去设置个游戏
I need you to set up a game…
也许那游戏 你现在还不很了解
…that may not be entirely clear to you right now.
但我向你保证 那些被测试的对象
But I assure you that the people being tested…
比你想像中更重要
…are part of something much larger.
他们是互相联系的
They're connected.
到最后 所有碎片会联系起来
So in the end, all the pieces will fit together…
一切会变得明朗
…and it'll be clear.
你是谁
Who are you?
- 阿曼达会让你失望的 - 等着瞧吧！
- Amanda will fail you. - We'll see.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
- 这是什么 - 是时候开始游戏了
- What's this? - It's time to play a game.
救命啊
Help.
救救我 这是什么
Help me. What is this?
这是什么 求你了
What is this? Please.
你为什么把我困在这里
Why are you keeping me here?
这里是什么地方 这里是什么地方
What is this place? What is this place?
我们本来都应该死掉的
We were all supposed to die.
他只是他妈的在测试你
He's just fucking testing you.
我女儿在哪
Where is my daughter?
救命啊
Help!
他没活过来
He didn't make it.
所有人都没活过来
Nobody made it.
而你就充当英雄的角色
You were supposed to be the hero.
彼得 你到底在哪里
Peter, where the hell are you?
有人吗？
Hello?
你接通了特勤探员彼得 斯莱姆的留言信箱
You've reached the voice mail for Special Agent Peter Strahm.
请留言吧！
Leave a message.
科万 我要定位斯莱姆的移动电话
Cowan, I wanna put a locator on Strahm's mobile phone.
马上办 先生
Right away, sir.
尽快回复我
Call me right back.
好的
Right.
- 这他妈的是什么 - 是我们的下一场恶梦
- What the hell is that? - It's our next nightmare.
这里有刀锋
There are blades in here.
是与门连着的
It's connected to the door.
烧杯被填满后 门就会开了
When the beaker fills up, the door opens.
用什么填满
Fills with what?
用血 我们的血
Blood. Our blood.
我想我们要把手伸进去
I think an arm is supposed to go in there…
然后用我们的血填满烧杯
…to fill the beaker.
什么 为什么我们不能用隔壁房的水
Wait. Why can't we just use the water from the other room?
不行 狭缝是闭上的
No, the slots are closed.
我们要伸手进去才能打开
We have to stick our arm in to keep them open,
但伸进去就拉不出来了
but they'd get stuck.
我们得关上那门
We need to close that door.
然后呢
So, what?
我们拼了性命来到这里？
We fight to the death,
最后牺牲一个人的鲜血 而另一个人则得到自由？
and one gets to freedom with the other person's blood?
嘿 等等 等等
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
你还拿着第一个房间的钥匙吗？
Do you still have the keys from that first room?
- 有 - 试一下那边的门
- Yeah. - Try one of them on that door.
- 不会有用的 - 也许会呢 这个有钥匙洞
- It won't work. - No, it might. This one has a keyhole.
这…这甚至不是同一把锁
It… It's not even the same lock.
为什么这机器有五个狭缝
Wait, why are there five slots in this machine?
不应该只有一个吗？
Shouldn't there only be one?
他们本来都有用的
They all would have worked.
找到你了 斯莱姆
There you are, Strahm.
好吧！我找到他了
All right. I got him.
我觉得这不是好主意
I don't think this is a good idea.
那浴缸不是留给一个人的
The tub wasn't meant for one person.
我们本应该每人拿着一根电线
We were supposed to hold one cable each…
那样就只会被小电击一下
…and suffer a small shock.
那是为五个人设置好的
It was meant for five people.
所有的游戏都是
They all were. Every game.
在第一个房间 我们只需要一把钥匙
We only needed one key in the first room.
他们都可以用的
They all worked,
任何一把钥匙都能打开所有项圈
and any one of them would have opened every collar.
在第二个房间
In the second room,
三个洞都不是只能容纳一个人
the three tubes were large enough for more than one person.
我们本应该合作 那样我们都能够存活
We were supposed to work together so we all survived.
这才是游戏的玩法
That's the game.
你们的本能会驱使你们做出行动
Your instincts will tell you to do one thing…
但我恳求你们做出相反的行动
…but I implore you to do the opposite.
噢 天啊
Oh, God.
是啊 他妈的太好了
Yeah. Big fucking whoops.
你们好 欢迎来到这里
Hello, and welcome.
这个旅程是为了让你们去探索
This journey has been one of discovery…
希望你们已经发现
…and hopefully you've discovered…
整体比部分更重要
…that the whole is greater than the sum of its parts.
举个例子说
The human body, for instance,
人体是自然界最耐用的杰作
is an astoundingly durable creation.
它含有大约10品脱的血液
It contains approximately 10 pints of blood…
然而 哪怕只剩下一半 人体还是能正常运作
…yet it is still able to operate with just half of that.
你们面前的装置代表着牺牲
The device before you is one of sacrifice.
血液的牺牲
A sacrifice of blood.
要想打开门
In order to open the door,
烧杯必须被填满到标注的刻度
the beaker must be filled to the marked level…
这个刻度并不是巧合
…a level that is of no coincidence.
至于用谁的鲜血
This amount can come from any one of you.
并不重要 时间才是最重要的
That does not matter. What does matter is time.
15分钟后 如果烧杯没被填入鲜血
For in 15 minutes, if the beaker is not filled…
炸弹将会被引爆 大门就会永远被封死
…the bombs will explode and the doors will be sealed forever.
所以现在我问你们
So now I ask you,
为了生存 你们愿意牺牲多少鲜血呢
how much blood will you give in order to survive?
他妈的 他妈的
Fuck! Fuck.
好吧！那么可以让一个人
All right, so one person can fill the beaker…
用10品脱的血填满烧杯 然后死掉
…with ten pints of blood and die.
或者两个人同时填
Or two people can fill it…
只用5品脱
…with five pints…
也许能活下去
…and maybe live.
我们要怎么做
What are we gonna do?
我说谎了
I lied.
我认识那个调查记者 他叫查尔斯
I know the investigative journalist in there. His name is Charles.
他在写一篇关于我所做的事的文章
He was writing a story about what I did.
你做了什么
What'd you do?
一个商人给了我
A dealer gave me…
一盎司海洛因 只要我烧掉一栋废弃的楼
…an ounce of heroin to burn down an abandoned building.
但这…
But it wa…
噢 天啊 那并不是废弃的楼 有八个人在那里
Oh, God. It wasn't abandoned. There was eight people in there.
八个人死了
Eight people died.
联邦政府插手调查了
And the feds got involved.
我被逮住后 我老爸花钱让我脱身了
And I got caught but I made a deal and my dad got me off.
那个和我做交易的人消失了
The guy who hired me disappeared and nothing happened.
然后什么事都没有发生
Nothing happened.
所以她才认识我
That's how she knew me.
那个死在浴缸的女人
The woman in the tub.
是火把我们联系起来了
The fire. It's what connects us.
那消防调查员写了事故的假报告
The fire inspector who wrote the bogus accident report…
那城市规划局的女人受贿
…the city planner…
批了建新楼的提议
…who pushed through the residential permits…
那个记者隐瞒了真相
…the journalist that buried the investigative story…
吸毒的富家小子放了火
…the rich- kid junkie who was the patsy…
房地产的发展商让一切计划实施起来
…and the real estate developer who set it all in motion.
我们杀了八个人 然后得到了房产权
We killed eight people and stole the property,
但没有人在意
and nobody cared.
没有人在意吗？
Nobody cared?
那八个人和他们的家人会在意
Eight people and their families cared.
联邦政府会 看看我他妈的手
The feds cared. Look at my fucking arm.
我在意 我在意
I cared! I cared!
但你没有得到公正审判
But you didn't face justice.
我们都没有
None of us did.
他们为什么这么做
Why did they all do it?
为什么 是因为钱吗？
Why? Was it for money?
这就是你的计划？你就是幕后黑手？
This was your plan? You were the one behind it?
那楼有八个人在
There was eight people in that building.
你必须知道的 明白吗？
You had to know that. Did you know that?
你是怪物
You're a monster.
你也是
So are you.
我们来到这里都是应得的
We both deserve to be here.
我一个人做不了 看着我 我一个人做不了
I can't do this alone. Look at me. I can't do this alone.
好的 没事的
Okay. It's okay.
我们数三声
We have to go on three.
一
One.
二
Two.
把你的手放进洞里
Put your hand in the hole!
三
Three!
你好 斯莱姆探员
Hello, Agent Strahm.
如果你现在听到这录音
If you are hearing this,
那说明你再一次找到了你要找的东西
then you have once again found what you're looking for.
或者你是这么认为的
Or so you think.
你的奉献值得嘉许
Your dedication is to be commended.
但我问你 你是否在你的…
But I ask you if you have…
探索旅途中学到了什么
…learned anything on your journey of discovery.
俗话说
As the old adage goes:
「被愚弄一次 是你的耻辱」
"Fool me once, shame on you.
「被愚弄两次 则是我的耻辱」
Fool me twice, shame on me."
你让自己陷入了需要信任的境况
The situation you find yourself in is one of trust.
所以我问你 特勤探员斯莱姆
So I ask you, Special Agent Strahm,
你学会相信我了吗？
have you learned to trust me?
想在这房里存活下来的唯一办法就是…
The only way to survive this room is…
…进入你前面的玻璃盒子
…by entering the glass box before you.
疼痛是会有的 但你有机会活下去
Pain will be incurred, but you have a chance of survival.
我们做到了
We did it.
我们赢了
We won.
我逮到你了 你狗娘养的
I got you, you motherfucker.
放下
Drop it!
我说放下
I said drop it!
谁对你干了这事
Who did this to you?
我们赢了
We won.
我们一起合作
We worked together.
我需要紧急医疗救治 圣博斯大街1293号
I need immediate medical assistance. 1293 Sandburst Drive.
天啊 彼得
Jesus, Peter.
告诉我怎样打开
Tell me how to open it.
我要怎样打开
How do I open it?
然而 如果你选择不进去 将不会有人再见到你
However, if you choose not to, you will never be heard from again.
你的尸体永远不会被发现
Your body will never be found.
你会永久消失
You will simply vanish.
我问你 特勤探员斯莱姆
I ask you, Special Agent Strahm,
你学会相信我了吗？
have you learned enough to trust me?
你会听从我的忠告吗？
Will you heed my warning?
- 因为如果你不… - 去你妈的
- For if you do not… - Fuck you.
这间房将永远是你的坟墓
…this room will forever be your tomb.
我的遗物将会与你永随
And my legacy will become yours.
如果你擅长猜测人的思想
If you're good at anticipating the human mind…
- 我觉得我被跟踪了 - 谁会跟踪你
- I think I'm being followed. - Who would be following you?
我要再跟吉尔·塔克再谈一次
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time.
他怀疑某个内部的人
He suspected someone on the inside.
偶然就会变成必然了
It leaves nothing to chance.
我们本来都应该死掉的
We were all supposed to die.
你就充当英雄的角色
You were supposed to be the hero.
做抉择吧！
Make your choice.
科万
Cowan.
是的 我是埃里克森
Yeah, this is Erickson.
我要你发布一则通缉令
I want you to put out an APB.
疑犯名字是彼得 斯莱姆
Suspect's name is Peter Strahm.
是的 没错
Yeah, that's right.
特勤探员彼得 斯莱姆
Special Agent Peter Strahm.
我会阻止你的 你狗娘养的
I'm gonna stop you, you son of a bitch.
我知道你是谁 我知道
I know who you are. I know.